increase the policy repo rate by fifty
basis points to 2543 per cent. In this, it was also decided to reinvent focused on the
soil
of accommodation to ensure that inflation remains with the
target doing further business
supporting growth. After this announcement, it was decided
that the bank will increase the EMI of your loan
and taking a loan will become expensive. Something
similar happened and its effect was decided just a day later.
After the announcement of RBI, two big
banks of the country have decided to make their loans expensive. The
country's largest private
sector bank ICICI Bank and Punjab
National Bank have decided to increase their lending rates.
ICICI Bank has decided to
increase its external benchmark prime lending rate.
This has come into effect from 5 August 2022.
Whereas after the decision of the country's second largest public
sector bank Punjab National Bank to
increase the interest rate, this rate has become
zero percent. Due to this, their
interest rates will become expensive.
Banks are not allowed to lend at lower rates.
PNB has decided to increase its RBI-related repo
limit lending rate.
It has now become
7.90 from 7.40. These new rates will come into effect from August 8, 2022.
Earlier this month,
ICICI Bank had made changes
in its rate directly before the RBI announced a repo rate hike.
Banks consider their lending rates as
repo rates, hence,
changes in repo rates impact loan interest.
To control inflation, the central
bank has increased the repo rate. Retail
inflation has remained above seven percent for a consecutive time. On
Friday, Reserve Bank Governor
Shaktikanta Das announced a 20 percent repo rate
hike, after which the
repo rate has reached 5.40. Reserve Bank
Governor Shaktikanta Das said that
inflation is at record levels across the world and the country is
facing high inflation rates.
June is the sixth consecutive month in which
retail inflation has exceeded the Reserve Bank's upper
limit.
2016 consecutive
months when headline CPI inflation
remained inches and now free offer tolerance level
of 6% Looking ahead this information
project which continues to give a continent upon the evolving
political
developments international commodity market
dynamics global financial market
developments and the special and temporal
distribution of the southwest monsoon
taking into account dr two factors and
only absorption of normal monsoon in
twenty-20 2 and average crude oil price
at Indian basket roof US dollar 105 per
viral inflation spray question 6.7 per
cent in
2223 curvilinear which you to edit 7.1 plus to
sure 386 officer thank you for its 5.8 per
cent respectively balance CPI
inflation for the first quarter of
next financial year
2324 this project direct 5 per cent on
[music]